<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Install MacPorts on The MacPorts Project</title>
    <link>https://constantin-p.github.io/macports-site/docs/installing/macports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Install MacPorts on The MacPorts Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2002–2019 [The MacPorts Project](https://www.macports.org/). All rights reserved.</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://constantin-p.github.io/macports-site/docs/installing/macports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS Package Install</title>
      <link>https://constantin-p.github.io/macports-site/docs/installing/macports/binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://constantin-p.github.io/macports-site/docs/installing/macports/binary/</guid>
      <description>The macOS package installer automatically installs MacPorts, sets the shell environment, and runs a selfupdate operation to update the ports tree and MacPorts base with the latest release.
 Download the latest MacPorts-2.5.4-....pkg installer from the releases on GitHub. Here are direct links for the latest versions of macOS:
 macOS 10.14 Mojave:
MacPorts-2.5.4-10.14-Mojave.pkg
 macOS 10.13 High Sierra:
MacPorts-2.5.4-10.13-HighSierra.pkg
 macOS 10.12 Sierra:
MacPorts-2.5.4-10.12-Sierra.pkg
  Double-click the downloaded package installer to perform the default “easy” install.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source Install</title>
      <link>https://constantin-p.github.io/macports-site/docs/installing/macports/source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://constantin-p.github.io/macports-site/docs/installing/macports/source/</guid>
      <description>If you installed MacPorts using the package installer, skip this section. To install MacPorts from the source code, follow the steps below.
 Download and extract the MacPorts 2.5.4 tarball. Either do so using your browser and the Finder, or use the given commands in a terminal window. curl -O https://distfiles.macports.org/MacPorts/MacPorts-2.5.4.tar.bz2 tar xf MacPorts-2.5.4.tar.bz2  Afterwards, perform the commands shown in the terminal window. If you wish to use a path other than /opt/local, follow the instructions for installing multiple copies of MacPorts instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Install</title>
      <link>https://constantin-p.github.io/macports-site/docs/installing/macports/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://constantin-p.github.io/macports-site/docs/installing/macports/git/</guid>
      <description>If you installed MacPorts using the package installer, skip this section.
There are times when some may want to run MacPorts from a version newer than the current stable release. Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a new feature that you&amp;rsquo;d like to use, or it fixes an issue you&amp;rsquo;ve encountered, or you just like to be on the cutting edge. These steps explain how to setup MacPorts for developers, using only Git to keep MacPorts up to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Multiple MacPorts Copies</title>
      <link>https://constantin-p.github.io/macports-site/docs/installing/macports/source.multiple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://constantin-p.github.io/macports-site/docs/installing/macports/source.multiple/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally a MacPorts developer may wish to install more than one MacPorts instance on the same host. Only one copy of MacPorts may use the default prefix /opt/local, so for additional installations use the option --prefix as shown below. It&amp;rsquo;s also recommended to change the applications dir using &amp;ndash;with-applications-dir to avoid conflicts in /Applications/MacPorts. Use --without-startupitems to automatically set startupitem_install no in the new macports.conf, which is required to avoid conflicts in /Library/LaunchAgents or /Library/LaunchDaemons.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>